Good news, everyone.
Tomorrow, you'll be making a delivery
to Ebola 9, the virus planet.
Why can't they go today?
Because tonight's a special night
and I want all of you to be alive.
It's the Academy of Inventors'
annual symposium.
Wow. I love symposia.
It's the event of the scientific season.
Every member presents an invention
and the best one wins the Academy prize.
Sounds boring.
Oh, my, yes, but not this year
because my latest invention is unbeatable.
Behold,
the death clock.
Simply jam your finger in the hole
and this readout tells you
exactly how long you have left to live.
Does it really work?
Well, it's occasionally off
by a few seconds,
what with free will and all.
Sounds like fun.
How long do I have to live?
Ooh, dibs on his CD player!
Who's the gross nerd?
That's me, at the very first symposium.
I'm the Academy's
oldest living member, you know.
These youngsters all look up to me.
Well, well, well.
Look who decided
to show his wrinkled face.
Why don't you
just leave me alone, Wernstrom?
Face it, Farnsworth, you're over the hill.
It's time to leave science
to the 120-year-olds.
You young turks think you know everything.
I was inventing things
when you were barely turning senile.
Go home before
you embarrass yourself, old man.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'm going to take a nap
before the ceremonies.
Who's that jerk?
A hundred years ago,
he was my most promising student
at Mars University,
but then, after one fateful pop quiz...
A-minus?
No one gives Ogden Wernstrom an A-minus.
I'm sorry, but penmanship counts.
I swear I'll have my revenge
if it takes me a hundred years.
And here it is
Slightly over 99 years later
and still no revenge.
I'm essentially in the clear.
I've been perusing
your fortified wine list
and I've selected the '71 Hobo's Delight,
the '57 Chateau Part-ay
and the '66 Thunder-Schewitz.
Exquisite choices, sir.
And mix them all together in a big jug.
Welcome to this year's Academy symposium.
I'm your host, Ron Popeil,
inventor of Mr. Microphone,
the spray-on toupee
and, of course, the technology
to keep human heads alive in jars.
But wait, there's more!
We've got a whole lineup
of inventors tonight,
starting with
that up-and-coming young star,
Ogden Wernstrom.
Boo!
More wine!
Distinguished members of the Academy,
I present to you the reverse scuba suit.
Observe.
Fetch.
Now sit.
I said sit!
Bad fish!
- Oh...
- Don't worry, Professor.
It's no competition for your death clock.
And what will you be presenting
this evening, Grandpa?
Let's just say it'll put
you young whippersnappers in your place.
I just hope it's not as lame
as that death clock
you presented last year.
- Eh, "last year," you say?
- That's right.
Oh, my.
Did it put you young whippersnappers
in your place?
Hardly.
We laughed until our teeth fell out.
Come along, Cinnamon.
Oh, dear.
I'll have to invent something new
in the next 10 minutes,
perhaps some sort of death clock.
Uh, professor?
Our last presentation
comes from our oldest member,
Professor Hubert Farnsworth.
Professor?
Uh... Just a second. Just a second.
Pencils down, prune face.
Oh, yes, here I am.
Okay, now. Hello there.
Now, we all know telescopes
allow us to see distant objects,
but what if we want
to smell distant objects?
Well, now we can,
thanks to my new invention,
the Smelloscope.
The odor travels past
this coffee stain here,
around the olive pit
and into this cigar burn.
And this appears to be a... a...
doodle of myself as a cowboy.
But the Smelloscope
is brilliant, I tell you!
Think of the astronomical odors
you'll smell, thanks to me!
Oh, my.
I've waited a hundred years
for this, Farnsworth.
I give your invention
the worst grade imaginable,
an A-minus-minus!
And now for the presentation of the award.
Listen, folks,
I'm practically giving this prize away
to Dr. Wernstrom for his fish thingy.
Perhaps 149 is just too old
to be a scientist.
- Yep.
- No, Professor. Don't give up.
There were plenty of times in my century
when I was gonna give up,
but I never did. Never.
Hey, are you even listening to me?
Oh, I give up.
By God, you're right!
I'm going to build that Smelloscope.
Eureka!
Did you build the Smelloscope?
No. I remembered
that I built one last year.
Go ahead, try it.
You'll find that every heavenly body
has its own particular scent.
Here, I'll point it at Jupiter.
Smells like strawberries.
Exactly.
And now Saturn.
Pine needles.
Oh, man, this is great.
As long as you don't make me smell Uranus.
I don't get it.
I'm sorry, Fry,
but astronomers renamed Uranus in 2620
to end that stupid joke once and for all.
Oh. What's it called now?
Urectum.
- Here, let me locate it for you.
- How about...
No, no, I think I'll just
smell around a bit over here.
Hmm.
What is it?
Oh, jeez, oh, man!
Remarkable!
A stench so foul,
it's right off the funk-o-meter.
I daresay, Fry may have discovered
the smelliest object
in the known universe.
Ooh, ooh, name it after me!
I think it's moving.
Hmm. Perhaps the computer
can calculate its trajectory.
My God!
Whatever it is,
it's headed straight for us
with enough force to reduce
this entire city to a stinky crater!
We have less than 72 hours.
Well, let's get lootin'.
So this thing's gonna
destroy the whole city?
What the heck is it?
Ah, just as I thought.
The answer lies in this movie
I found on the Internet.
New York City, the year 2000.
The most wasteful society
in the history of the galaxy,
and it was running out of places
to bury its never-ending
output of garbage.
The landfills were full.
New Jersey was full.
And so, under cover of darkness,
the city put its garbage out to sea
on the world's largest barge.
The repulsive barge
circledthe oceans for 50 years
but no country would accept it,
not even that really filthy one.
You know the one I mean.
Finally, in 2052, the cityused
its mob connections to obtain a rocket
and launch the garbage Into outer space.
Some experts claim the ball
might return to Earth someday,
but their concerns were dismissed
as "depressing."
Wow, you got that off the Internet?
In my day, the Internet was only used
to download pornography.
Actually, that's still true.
Now that the garbage is in space, doctor,
perhaps you can help me
with my sexual inhibitions.
With gusto.
Aw.
So that's the situation.
Due to the shortsightedness
of Old New York,
New New York is going to be destroyed
by a giant ball of garbage.
Fry, what the hell
were you people thinking back then?
How could you just
throw your garbage away?
Hey, hey, give me a break.
What do you do with it?
We recycle everything.
Robots are made from old beer cans.
Yeah, and this beer can
is made out of old robots.
And that sandwich you're eating
is made from old discarded sandwiches.
Nothing just gets thrown away.
The future is disgusting.
Typical 20th-century attitude.
Hey, you have no right
to criticize the 20th century.
We gave the world the light bulb,
the steamboat, and the cotton gin.
Those things are all
from the 19th century.
Yeah, well, they probably just copied us.
Please, there's no time for this now.
This is an emergency.
We must warn the mayor.
Garbage ball, huh? That sounds serious.
Very serious, Mayor Poopenmeyer.
I gotta sure this isn't
another scientific fraud
like global warming or secondhand smoke.
Send in my science advisor.
Wernstrom!
Well, well, well.
Come to present
your latest napkin, Professor?
No, I'm here because a giant trash ball
is heading straight for us.
Smell for yourself.
Holy... Gee!
That smell could be anything.
A faulty stench coil,
some cheese on the lens, who knows?
Mr. Mayor, we just got
this transmission from Neptune.
Giant garbage ballpassed close by.
Horrible stench!
The transmission cuts out there, sir.
No, I guess it keeps going.
There we go.
My God! The senile old man is right!
Do you mean him or me?
- Him.
- Oh.
Next, New New York in crisis.
- Morbo?
- Thanks, human female.
Puny Earthlings were shocked today
to learn that a ball of garbage
will destroy
their pathetic city of New New York.
Makes me glad we live here in Los Angeles.
Morbo agrees.
Can't we just shoot a missile at it?
We've simulated that on a supercomputer,
but the ball is just too damn gooey.
A missile would go right through it.
But suppose we sent a crew
to plant an explosive
precisely on the fault line
between this mass of coffee grounds
and this deposit
of America Online floppy disks.
In theory, it could work.
Uh, in theory, perhaps,
but you'll never find a crew willing to
take on a mission so suicidally dangerous.
Ah, crap.
Now, you'll only have
one chance to destroy the ball.
After that, it will be so close to Earth
that blowing it up
would cause garbage to rain
over the entire planet,
killing billions.
Aw, boo-hoo.
Now here's the bomb I've prepared.
Once you activate it,
you'll have 25 minutes to get away.
That's all? But...
Now, now.
There'll be plenty of time
to discuss your objections
when and if you return.
Odor at magnitude 8.
Magnitude 12.
Magnitude 31.
We're breaking up.
Turn on the anti-smell device.
Hmm, sporty.
Wow!
Look at all this filth.
It's not filth.
It's a glorious monument
to the achievements of the 20th century.
Look, a real Beanie Baby.
Oh, a Mr. Spock collectors' plate.
Some Bart Simpson dolls.
Eat my shorts.
Okay.
Mmm, shorts.
Fry, this stuff
was garbage when it was new.
Let's blow it up already.
This junk isn't garbage.
I can dig in any random pile
and find something great.
All right, let's get to work.
Let's see.
If that's hypodermic ridge,
then the bomb must go right here.
Get ready to run.
We've got 25 minutes.
Uh, 15 minutes.
Five minutes.
Six-h minutes?
Hmm.
There's your problem.
The professor put
the counter on upside down.
That idiot.
It wasn't set for 25 minutes.
It was set for 52 seconds.
Ahhh! We're gonna die!
- Right?
- Right.
Ahhh!
It's gonna blow!
Hey, watch it!
You'll put somebody's eye out!
Okay, okay, keep your space pants on.
I'll take care of this.
We're saved.
Yeah, but this garbage ball's
unstoppable now.
New New York is done for.
All in all, this is one day
Mittens the kitten won't soon forget.
Kittens give Morbo gas.
In lighter news,
the city of New New York is doomed.
Blame rests with known human
Professor Hubert Farnsworth
and his tiny inferior brain.
Aw! How could I have put
that bomb timer on upside down?
I could swear I followed
the manual precisely.
I'm a dried-up husk of a scientist.
This is all my fault.
No, it's my fault, too.
I'm sure I threw out
more than my share of that trash up there.
Also, one month, my toilet broke
and I just went straight
in the garbage can.
Leela was right.
The people of the 20th century
were idiotic slobs.
Especially me.
Enough. You all failed miserably.
It's time to put
a real scientist in charge.
- Wernstrom!
- The very same.
Dr. Wernstrom, can you save my city?
Of course, but it'll cost you.
- First, I'll need tenure.
- Done.
- And a big research grant.
- You got it.
Also access to a lab
and five graduate students,
at least three of them Chinese.
All right. All right, done.
- What's your plan?
- What plan?
I'm set for life.
Au revoir, suckers.
That rat. Do something.
I wish I could, but he's got tenure.
Hmm?
It's time to take action.
Stephanie, cancel the maid for today.
Have her come tomorrow.
Well, I'm out of ideas.
Anyone?
Wait.
If we could build an object
the exact size, density,
and consistency of the garbage ball,
it might just knock the ball away
without smashing it to bits.
But where can we find a substance
the exact density
and consistency as garbage?
Alas, I don't know.
Uh, what about garbage?
Good Lord!
A second ball of garbage.
That just might work.
But garbage isn't something you just find
lying in the streets of Manhattan.
This city's been garbage-free
for 500 years.
Well, then it's time to make some more.
Make garbage? But how?
Stand back and watch the master.
This Slurm can?
Now it's garbage.
These papers?
Garbage.
This picture of your wife?
Pure garbage. Now you try it.
By God, I think the boy's got something.
Come on, everyone.
The fate of the city's at stake.
Good.
Don't finish that cruller. Throw it away.
Bender, drink that beer
and drop the bottle on the ground.
Very nice.
Get that robot some more beer.
Hmm?
We've trashed this room
but that's just a start.
We've got to get Fry's message
to the people.
People of New New York,
take a lesson from the 20th century,
stop all this pain-in-the-ass recycling
and throw your garbage on the floor.
Go ahead, just chuck it
any old place like I used to.
Your city is counting on you.
If my calculations are correct,
this garbage ball will knock
the other garbage ball
directly into the sun.
And if my calculations are correct,
we're all going to die horribly.
Ha-ha-ha-ha, ha-ha!
Ha...
All right, places, everyone.
Prepare for launch.
Five, four, three, two...
Three, four, five, six...
Just fire the damn thing.
Oops.
Burning garbage.
It worked!
And so, on behalf of the entire city,
I thank you, Professor Farnsworth.
I now present you with the Academy prize
which we confiscated from Dr. Wernstrom
after it became apparent
that he was a jackass.
Yes! In your face, Wernstrom!
I'll get you, Farnsworth,
even if it takes another hundred years.
And, Fry, we owe you
a tremendous debt as well.
Were it not for
your 20th-century garbage-making skills,
we'd all be buried
under 20th-century garbage.
Should we really be celebrating?
I mean, what if this second garbage ball
returns to Earth like the first one did?
Well, who cares?
That won't be for hundreds of years.
Exactly. It's none of our concern.
That's the 20th-century spirit.
We'll meet again
Don't know where
And I don't know when
But I know we'll meet again
Some sunny day
Oh, keep smiling through